[
  {
    "question": "In the Roman numeral system, letters represent numbers. How is the year 2024 represented in Roman numerals?",
    "correct": "MMXXIV",
    "incorrect": ["MMXXVI", "MMXLII", "MLXVI", "MMXXXII", "MMXVI"]
  },
  {
    "question": "China and Russia border the most nations (14). Which of these countries do not border China?",
    "correct": "Uzbekistan",
    "incorrect": ["North Korea", "Russia", "Mongolia", "Kazakhstan", "Kyrgyzstan", "Tajikistan", "Afghanistan", "Pakistan", "India", "Nepal", "Bhutan", "Myanmar", "Laos", "Vietnam"]
  },
  {
    "question": "How many adverbs are in the following quote by Maya Angelou, “Hoping for the best, prepared for the worst, and unsurprised by anything in between.“",
    "correct": "0",
    "incorrect": ["1", "2", "3", "4", "5"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Pi is an irrational number with an infinite sequence of digits. What is the third digit of pi squared?",
    "correct": "6",
    "incorrect": ["0", "1", "2", "3", "4", "5", "7", "8", "9"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Before the Declaration of Independence, the United States comprised thirteen colonies governed by the Kingdom of Great Britain. In which century did the United States gain independence?",
    "correct": "18th Century",
    "incorrect": ["15th Century", "16th Century", "17th Century", "19th Century"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The bubonic plague can cause severe and deadly symptoms. However, which of these is not a typical symptom of the bubonic plague?",
    "correct": "Coughing",
    "incorrect": ["Buboes", "Fever", "Headache", "Chills", "Weakness", "Vomiting", "Diarrhea", "Nausea"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Every U.S. state has a motto representing its values or ideals. Which of these is not a motto of any U.S. state?",
    "correct": "A Mari Usque Ad Mare",
    "incorrect": ["Audemus jura nostra defender", "North to the Future", "Ditat Deus", "Regnat Populus", "Eureka", "Nil Sine Numine", "Qui Transtulit Sustinet", "Liberty and Independence", "In God We Trust", "Wisdom, Justice, Moderation", "Ua Mau ke Ea o ka ‘Āina i ka Pono", "Esto Perpetua", "State Sovereignty, National Union.", "The Crossroads of America", "Our liberties we prize, and our rights we will maintain.", "Ad Astra per Aspera", "United we stand, divided we fall", "Union, Justice, Confidence", "Dirigo", "Fatti maschii, parole femine", "Ense Petit Placidam Sub Libertate Quietem", "Si quaeris peninsulam amoenam circumspice", "L'etoile du Nord", "Virtute et Armis", "Salus Populi Suprema Lex Esto", "Oro y Plata", "Equality Before the Law", "All for our country", "Live Free or Die", "Liberty and Prosperity", "Crescit eundo", "Excelsior", "Esse quam videri", "With God, all things are possible", "Labor omnia vincit", "Alis Volat Propriis", "Virtue, Liberty and Independence", "Hope", "Dum Spiro Spero", "Under God the People Rule", "Agriculture and Commerce", "Friendship", "Industry", "Freedom and Unity", "Sic Semper Tyrannis", "Al-ki", "Montani Semper Liberi", "Forward", "Equal Rights"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Russia is divided between Europe and Asia, and many of its major cities lie in the European part. Which of these cities is not located in European Russia?",
    "correct": "Novosibirsk",
    "incorrect": ["Moscow", "Saint Petersburg", "Kazan", "Nizhny Novgorod", "Ufa", "Samara", "Rostov-on-Don", "Krasnodar", "Voronezh", "Perm", "Volgograd"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The president of the United States is both the head of state and head of government. If the date was January 1, 2021, how many U.S. presidents would there have been in history?",
    "correct": "45",
    "incorrect": ["40", "41", "42", "43", "44", "46"]
  },
  {
    "question": "A figure of speech is a creative way of using language to convey meaning. What figure of speech is present in the sentence “Winning that championship quiz bowl match wasn’t an easy task“?",
    "correct": "Litotes",
    "incorrect": ["Simile", "Personification", "Alliteration", "Onomatopoeia", "Oxymoron", "Pun", "Synecdoche"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Aristotle and Plato are key figures in ancient philosophy, known for their foundational works on ethics and politics. Plato is to the Republic as Aristotle is to?",
    "correct": "Nicomachean Ethics",
    "incorrect": ["Symposium", "Apology", "Euthyphro", "Phaedo", "Allegory of the cave", "First Alcibiades", "Hippias Major"]
  },
  {
    "question": "A derivative is the instantaneous rate of change of a function with respect to its input. What would the derivative of sec²x be?",
    "correct": "2sec²(x)tan(x)",
    "incorrect": ["sec²(x)tan(x)", "sec²(x)", "2sec²(x)", "-2sec²(x)tan(x)", "2sec²(x)cot(x)", "1", "0"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Steven Spielberg is widely regarded as one of the greatest film directors of all time and is the most commercially successful director in film history. Which of these films was not directed by him?",
    "correct": "Jurassic World",
    "incorrect": ["Jurassic Park", "E.T. the Extra-Terrestrial", "Indiana Jones and the Kingdom of the Crystal Skull", "The Lost World: Jurassic Park", "War of the Worlds", "Ready Player One", "Saving Private Ryan", "Jaws", "Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade", "Raiders of the Lost Ark", "The Adventures of Tintin", "Minority Report", "Catch Me If You Can", "Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom", "Schindler's List", "Close Encounters of the Third Kind"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The shortest war in history was between the United Kingdom and the Sultanate of Zanzibar on August 27, 1896, lasting approximately 40 minutes. Zanzibar eventually merged with Tanganyika to form which modern nation?",
    "correct": "Tanzania",
    "incorrect": ["Kenya", "Uganda", "Rwanda", "Burundi", "Democratic Republic of the Congo", "Zambia", "Malawi", "Mozambique"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The SAT is a standardized test developed by the College Board and is widely used for college admissions in the United States. What was the SAT originally called?",
    "correct": "Scholastic Aptitude Test",
    "incorrect": ["Scholastic Achievement Test", "Student Assessment Test", "Scholastic Ability Test", "Scholastic Assessment Test", "Student Aptitude Test", "Student Achievement Test", "Student Ability Test"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Now primarily focused on his philanthropic efforts, which businessman became the first centibillionaire (net worth of 100 billion)?",
    "correct": "Bill Gates",
    "incorrect": ["Warren Buffett", "Jeff Bezos", "Elon Musk", "Bernard Arnault", "Mark Zuckerberg", "Carlos Slim"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Ivy League contains eight globally-renowned universities associated with academic excellence. Which Ivy League school was originally established as the Collegiate School?",
    "correct": "Yale University",
    "incorrect": ["Harvard University", "Princeton University", "University of Pennsylvania", "Dartmouth College", "Cornell University", "Columbia University", "Brown University"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Mississippi River is the second longest river in North America only behind one of its tributaries, the Missouri River. Which U.S. state is the largest by total area (land and water) entirely east of the Mississippi?",
    "correct": "Michigan",
    "incorrect": ["Florida", "Wisconsin", "Georgia", "Illinois", "New York", "North Carolina"]
  },
  {
    "question": "This U.S. president earned the nickname “Old Tippecanoe“ after leading a military force against Tecumseh's confederacy at the Battle of Tippecanoe.",
    "correct": "William Henry Harrison",
    "incorrect": ["Andrew Jackson", "Zachary Taylor", "Franklin Pierce", "Andrew Johnson", "Ulysses S. Grant", "Rutherford B. Hayes", "James A. Garfield"]
  },
  {
    "question": "This tropical cyclone at its peak intensity was the largest tropical cyclone on record with a wind diameter of 1,380 mi (2,220 km) and had the lowest sea-level pressure ever at 870 mbar (25.69 inHg).",
    "correct": "Typhoon Tip",
    "incorrect": ["Hurricane Katrina", "Hurricane Patricia", "Cyclone Winston", "Bhola Cyclone", "Typhoon Nancy"]
  },
  {
    "question": "This violinist is often considered one of the greatest of all time was awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom and has won 16 Grammy Awards.",
    "correct": "Itzhak Perlman",
    "incorrect": ["Hilary Hahn", "Joshua Bell", "Nicola Benedetti", "Jascha Heifetz", "Yehudi Menuhin"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Marie Curie was a physicist and chemist known for her groundbreaking research on radioactivity and was the first person to have won two Nobel Prizes. What is the name of her husband with whom she shared the 1903 Nobel Prize in Physics?",
    "correct": "Pierre",
    "incorrect": ["Paul", "Louis", "Jean", "Joseph", "Henri", "Charles", "Albert"]
  },
  {
    "question": "By 1860, many world borders had become generally recognizable to modern-day borders. Which of these countries did not exist in the year 1860?",
    "correct": "Mughal Empire",
    "incorrect": ["United States of America", "Great Qing", "Russian Empire", "Tokugawa Shogunate", "United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland", "Guarded Domains of Iran", "Empire of Brazil", "Great Joseon State", "Ottoman Empire"]
  },
  {
    "question": "This pharaoh was the third of the 18th Dynasty of Egypt known for defeating the Kingdom of Kush and destroying Kerma in Nubia.",
    "correct": "Thutmose I",
    "incorrect": ["Tutankhamun", "Ramesses II", "Amenhotep I", "Cleopatra VII", "Khufu", "Amenhotep III", "Thutmose III"]
  },
  {
    "question": "In Sikhism, the Five Ks are items that Guru Gobind Singh in 1699 commanded Khalsa Sikhs to wear at all times. Which is not one of the five items?",
    "correct": "Kamarkasa",
    "incorrect": ["Kesh", "Kangha", "Kara", "Kachera", "Kirpan"]
  },
  {
    "question": "This author, known for exploring existential themes, wrote a novel where the protagonist murders his invalid wife by drowning her in a lake. His other works include The Fall and The Plague. Name this author of The Stranger, a key figure in absurdism.",
    "correct": "Albert Camus",
    "incorrect": ["Fyodor Dostoevsky", "Franz Kafka", "Jean-Paul Sartre", "Samuel Beckett", "Eugène Ionesco", "Saul Bellow"]
  },
  {
    "question": "This singer-songwriter began her career as a country artist after signing with Big Machine Records at age 15. Name this artist, who later became a global pop star.",
    "correct": "Taylor Swift",
    "incorrect": ["Carrie Underwood", "Tanya Tucker", "Dolly Parton", "Miley Cyrus"]
  },
  {
    "question": "This economist is best known for his development of general equilibrium theory, which describes how supply and demand interact across multiple markets simultaneously.",
    "correct": "Léon Walras",
    "incorrect": ["John Maynard Keynes", "Adam Smith", "Milton Friedman", "Paul Samuelson", "Alfred Marshall"]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Supreme Court decision from 1905 invalidated a law limiting bakers' working hours, ruling that it violated the 14th Amendment's right to freedom of contract. Name this controversial decision often cited as a key example of the court prioritizing economic liberties over labor regulations.",
    "correct": "Lochner v. New York",
    "incorrect": ["West Coast Hotel Co. v. Parrish", "Nebbia v. New York", "Loving v. Virginia", "Miranda v. Arizona", "Gitlow v. New York"]
  },
  {
    "question": "On October 1, 2024, this person became the first female president of Mexico. Name this woman who prior to serving as president was the Head of Government of Mexico City.",
    "correct": "Claudia Sheinbaum",
    "incorrect": ["Xóchitl Gálvez", "Josefina Vázquez Mota", "Olga Sánchez Cordero", "Norma Lucía Piña Hernández", "Rosa Icela Rodríguez", "Alicia Bárcena"]
  },
  {
    "question": "This college football team became the first to achieve 1000 wins after a 31-24 victory over Maryland on November 18, 2023. Name this university whose alumni include 8 domestic and foreign heads of state or heads of government.",
    "correct": "University of Michigan",
    "incorrect": ["University of Alabama", "Ohio State University", "Yale University", "Harvard University", "University of Pennsylvania", "Princeton University"]
  },
  {
    "question": "This Russian novel follows the mental anguish and moral dilemmas of Rodion Raskolnikov who plans to kill a pawnbroker. Name this novel often considered one of the greatest works of world literature.",
    "correct": "Crime and Punishment",
    "incorrect": ["War and Peace", "The Brothers Karamazov", "Day of the Oprichnik", "The Dream Life of Sukhanov", "Anna Karenina", "The Slynx"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The sun has not set on the British Empire in over two centuries. In October of 2024, the United Kingdom agreed to hand over sovereignty of the Chagos Islands to this nation. Name this country whose exclusive economic zone is more than 1000 times greater than its area.",
    "correct": "Mauritius",
    "incorrect": ["Maldives", "Seychelles", "Comoros", "Kenya", "Mozambique", "Tanzania", "Somalia", "Madagascar"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Dassler brothers created two of the largest shoe manufacturers in the world. Adolf Dassler founded Adidas while Rudolf Dassler founded what company?",
    "correct": "Puma",
    "incorrect": ["Nike", "ASICS", "Sketchers", "Under Armour", "Fila"]
  },
  {
    "question": "The Act Prohibiting Importation of Slaves took effect in what year which legally banned the importation of slaves into any port or place within the jurisdiction of the United States?",
    "correct": "1808",
    "incorrect": ["1865", "1812", "1827", "1799", "1840"]
  },
  {
    "question": "This person became the first black woman to be elected to the United States Congress. Name this politician who was posthumously awarded the Presidential Medal of Freedom by Barack Obama.",
    "correct": "Shirley Chisholm",
    "incorrect": ["Kamala Harris", "Barbara Jordan", "Carol Moseley Braun", "Sojourner Truth", "Alice Walker", "Harriet Tubman"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Often considered one of the greatest chess players of all time, name this player who is known as DrDrunkenstein on Lichess.",
    "correct": "Magnus Carlsen",
    "incorrect": ["Garry Kasparov", "Anatoly Karpov", "Hikaru Nakamura", "Fabiano Caruana", "Viswanathan Anand"]
  },
  {
    "question": "First identified as a distinct element in 1781, this element also known as wolfram has the atomic number 74. Name this metal which has the highest melting point of any element.",
    "correct": "Tungsten",
    "incorrect": ["Osmium", "Lead", "Chromium", "Molybdenum", "Gold"]
  },
  {
    "question": "In physics, kinematics is the study of the motion of points, bodies, and systems of bodies without considering the forces that cause them to move. Which of the following is one of the four kinematic equations?",
    "correct": "v = v₀ + at",
    "incorrect": ["x = v²/2a", "x = (v + v₀)t", "x = v₀t + ½a²t²", "v = v₀ + a/t", "v = vt + ½at"]
  },
  {
    "question": "Somnambulism is the medical term for what condition which occurs during the slow-wave NREM-3 stage of sleep?",
    "correct": "Sleepwalking",
    "incorrect": ["Insomnia", "Sleep Apnea", "Narcolepsy", "Nightmare Disorder", "Sleep Paralysis"]
  },
  {
    "question": "This city, known for its lavish casinos and luxury resorts, holds the title for the highest gambling revenue in the world.",
    "correct": "Macau",
    "incorrect": ["Las Vegas", "Monte Carlo", "Singapore", "London", "Paris"]
  }
]
